Mss.Prints
American Philosophical Society
Prints Collection
1500-2000
Mss.Prints
American Philosophical Society
1000.0 Item(s)
A large and growing collection containing photographs, engravings, lithographs, paintings on a number of topics. The Print Collection employs the following codes: Regular File—Persons, Places and things, Group pictures, Collections; Oversize—Persons, Places and things, Collections. Note: Refer to the Print Collection card file for specific subjects and reference citations.
Birch, William Russell, 1755-1834
Bodmer, Karl, 1809-1893
Eastman, Seth, 1808-1875
West, Benjamin, 1730-1813
Scope and Contents note
Native American Images Note: Up to 300 Native American images, dating from 1771-1966, representing as many as twenty-five tribes created by a variety of artists and photographers. Images as diverse as The Death of Miantonomo, General Harrison and Tecumseh, portraits of Sitting Bull and Pocahontas. Tribes depicted include the Isleta, Sioux, Seneca, Lenni Lenape, Osage, Shawnee, and Eskimos. Noted artists are Benjamin West, Seth Eastman, William Russell Birch, Frederic Remington, and Karl Bodmer. Material types are over one hundred black and white silver gelatin photographs, albumen prints, black and white engravings, color lithographs, and black and white posters. Of note, hand-colored lithographs of three person portraits of Osage Indians by Louis Boilly and individual portrait color lithographs by John T. Bowen of Iowa, Omaha, and Sioux chiefs. In William Russell Birch’s views of Philadelphia, the Native American related works are the "Back of the State House, Philadelphia" and "William Penn’s Treaty Tree." Subject related images from the Broadsides and the Garvan Collection are included. Note: Some Native American images from specific collections, such as, Franz Boas, Paul Wallace and Frank Speck are housed in the Print Collection.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950; Wallace, Paul A. W.; Albumen prints; Algonquian Indians; Cheyenne Indians; Creek Indians; Dakota Indians; Delaware Indians; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Engravings.; Eskimos--Greenland--Social life and customs; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of North America; Iroquois Indians; Isleta Indians; Kiowa Indians; Lithographs.; Narraganett Indians; Negatives; Omaha Indians; Osage Indians; Plains Indians; Posters; Powhatan Indians; Shawnee Indians; Southeast Indians
- Benjamin Franklin am hofe zu Versailles., ca. 1820; 1.0 Item(s)
- Benjamin Franklin, seated at desk., 1873; 1.0 Item(s)
- Works of the late Doctor Benjamin Franklin title page., 1793; 1.0 Item(s)
- Color engraving of Benjamin Franklin., n. d.
- Benjamin Franklin, brown tone, oval portrait., ca. 1800
- Benjamin Franklin in red coat., n. d.
- "Vertu et Travail.", n. d.
- Franklin and Electricity, 1752.
- Franklin, seated at table., n. d.
- Franklin Residence at Ecton, Northamptonshire., n. d.
- "Prof. Darwin," Figaro's London Sketchbook of Celebrities.
- "Mr. C. R. Darwin, Author of the Origin of Species."
- "The Contrast, or Things as they are."
- "Mad Tom's First Practical Essay on the Rights of Man."
- "A sure cure for all Paines"
- "A Democrat."
- "The End of Pain."
- "Hear and improve," he pertly cries, "I come to make all nations wise."
- APSdigobj3204
- "Two Pair of Portraits."
- "Tree of Liberty, with the Devil Tempting John Bull." 1798
- "London Corresponding Society."
- "Destruction of the French Gun Boats, or Little Boney and the Friend Talley in Hight Glee."
- "We Explain the Rights of Men to de Noblesse."
- The Absent Man.
- Thomas Paine
- Full length view of Thomas Paine, standing, holding copy of "Rights of Man."
- Profile portrait, identified by caption as Thomas Paine.
- Thomas Paine, portrait, as older man with hand in coat.
- "A radical reformer."
- "Cobbett at Coventry."
- "Mad Tom, or the Man of Rights."
- "Tom Paine's nightly pest."
- "Wha Wants Me" Cartoon associated with Thomas Paine.
- Thomas Paine, portrait, seated with book.
- Thomas Paine house.
- Thomas Paine house.
- Thomas Paine Monument, postcard.
- Thomas Paine Cottage, North and Paine Aves., New Rochelle, N.Y., postcard.
- Thomas Paine Memorial House, New Rochelle, NY, post card.
- One cent Benjamin Franklin stamp, 1892.
- Benjamin Franklin postage stamp, French.
- Benjamin Franklin postage stamp, Italian.
- Benjamin Franklin, 1/2 cent stamps.
- Benjamin Franklin, 250th Anniversary stamps.
- First Postmaster General, Benjamin Franklin, 1706-1790.
- Franklin stamp, 1/2 cent, Commemorating the 250th anniversary of Franklin's birth.
- Franklin stamp, two cents.
- Three cent postage stamp centenary, featuring portraits of Washington and Franklin, June 1947.
- One cent Franklin stamp.
- Green and gold one cent stamp, silhouette of Franklin in profile.
- Manual Labor Bank note with image of Benjamin Franklin.
- Bank note, Franklin Silk Company.
- "Neither War nor Peace."
- Seth Newhouse, 1842-1921
- Death of Miantonomo
- Gretomih, Kishagashugah, Minckchatahooh
- Medicine man curing a patient
- Myhangah, Washingasbha, Marchanthitahtoongah
- Sitting Bull
- The death cry
- The rainbow
- Hoboken Bank note with image of Franklin, 1829.
- Thomas Nuttall.